Miles J Phillips Developer, Data Engineer

I've recently made the leap from full time architect to data engineer. After a lifetime of tinkering with programming and technology, I've decided to make my passion my vocation. Having transitioned from a design & management career in construction into the technology sector, I bring unique perspectives to technical challenges and products including:

- Extensive experience delivering extremely complex projects by leading interdisciplinary teams with diverse stakeholders.
- A hunger to work on fast moving software projects, with an eye for detail and quality
- Well honed communication and briefing skills, along with technical knowledge and a teacher's knack for explaining complex ideas to non-technical stakeholders

Technical Skills

Cloud Infrastructure

Proficient in deploying, managing, and optimizing cloud infrastructure on AWS, leveraging Terraform for infrastructure as code. Skilled at managing data storage with S3, securing access with IAM, provisioning compute resources on EC2, building serverless applications with Lambda, and orchestrating data pipelines using Prefect.

Data Engineering

Adept at building and maintaining robust databases, APIs, and backend applications using Python, PostgreSQL, and FastAPI. Committed to data integrity through test-driven development practices and rigorous quality assurance.

Software Development

Experienced in developing multi-faceted applications following agile methodologies, test-driven development, and implementing comprehensive unit and integration testing for robust, high-quality software.

Programming Languages Python Js JavaScript THTML CSS

Tools & Frameworks 💠 Git 📭 PostgreSQL 🦖 Terraform 🕜 FastAPI 🔬 Linux 🐠 AWS 🕈 Prefect

Design & CAD Revit AutoCAD Vectorworks A Adobe CS Suite A Affinity SketchUp

Experience

Employer	Role	Dates
Northcoders	Data Engineer: Completed an intensive data engineering bootcamp, honing skills in data wrangling, ETL processes, and building scalable data pipelines. Delivered a final project (pending completion) showcasing proficiency in data pipeline infrastructure and orchestration.	Mar 2024- May 2024
TSH Architects	Director: Practice leader, including strategic responsibility for technology, IT, and resource management & reporting. Delivered over 20 successful projects across the South East ranging from $£300k$ to $£10M$ from conception to completion during my time at TSH.	2022-2023
	Associate : Heritage and refurbishement practice lead, growing relationships with new and existing clients including Lincoln College, Oxford, St John's College, Oxford and Rugby School.	2019-2022
	Senior Architect: Leading heritage, education and sports projects, including projects for Lincoln College, Oxford and St Hilda's Collge, Oxford. Improving office QA and standards adoption. Delivering BIM pilot projects.	2015-2019
	Associate Lecturer: Assisting with preparation, delivery and assessment of Construction Management degree-level courses. Developed new case studies and teaching resources for engaging construction management and quantity surveying students.	2021-2023
London Met University	Visiting Lecturer: Developing and delivering CAD courses for professionals.	2015-2018

Employer	Role	Dates
	Architect: Managing university projects up to £5M in value from feasibility to completion. Leading consultant teams. Working with sensitive listed buildings and churches.	2014–2015
	Part II Architectural Assistant	2011-2014
	Visiting Lecturer: Developing & delivering a course in technical drawing, digital imagery, 2D and 3D drafting and presentation skills. Reviewing and grading year-end presentations and submissions.	2012-2013

Volunteering		
Organisation	Role	Dates
	Videographer, Web & Graphic Consultancy: Writing, shooting, designing & producing documentary-style promotional videos. Consulting on branding and graphics. Assisting in developing and running workshops for children displaced from informal settlements.	Nov 2011- Jan 2011

Education		
School	Course	Year
The Bartlett, UCL	PGDip in Professional Practice & Management in Architecture (ARB/RIBA Part 3)	2014
University of Sheffield	M.Arch in Architecture (RIBA Part 2)	2010
	BA (Hons) Architecture, 2:1 (RIBA Part 1)	2006

Other Skills

Management & Strategy

Seasoned SME leader, including wide ranging responsibilities for strategy, profit & loss, employment and business development. Experience designing, creating and implementing profitability tracking tools.

Architecture

Experienced at all stages of design, leading and managing projects from inception to completion: feasibility, permissions, tender processes and Contract Administration. Well versed in UK development context.

Communication & Management

Skilled communicator, personable and sociable. Experienced at managing multiple projects, prioritisation, delegation, and working to tight deadlines.

Graphic Design

An eye for graphical presentation and clean, clear visual communication. Academic grounding in the theory and practice of information design.

Other

BIM & CAD
★ Technical Drawing Video Production 3D & Vizualisation

Interests

Accomplished vocalist and musician within classical, folk, pop and electronic music traditions. Regular hiker with wide experience of outdoor pursuits. Well travelled. Continuing interest in literature & philosophy.